<tool id="plotmds" name="Plot MDS" version="1.0.2">
    <description>
        Create a multidimensional scaling plot to identify outliers in samples
    </description>
    
    <stdio>
        <exit_code range="1:" level="fatal" description="Tool exception" />
    </stdio>
    
    <command interpreter="Rscript">
        plotMDS.R $countPath
                  $outDir
                  "$factData"
                  "$labelData"
                  $labelSize

    </command>
    
    <inputs>
        <param name="countPath" type="data" format="tabular" 
        	   label="Counts Data"
               help="No data? See help section below!"/>
        
        <param name="factData" type="text" size="100"
               label="Factor Levels"
               help="In order matching the columns of the counts matrix:
                     ie WT,WT,Mut,Mut,Mut,WT..."/>
               
        <param name="labelData" type="text" size="100"
               label="Sample Labels"
               help="In order matching the columns of the counts matrix:
                     ie Smpl1,Smpl2,Mut-Smpl1,Mut-Smpl2,Mut-Smpl3,Smpl3..."/>
               
        <param name="labelSize" type="float" value="1" min="0" max="2"
               label="Plot Labels Size"
               help="Reduce if labels are overlapping or running off plot"/>
    </inputs>
    
    <outputs>
        <data name="outDir" format="pdf" label="MDS Plot"/>
    </outputs>
    
    <help>
.. class:: warningmark

The input must be in tabular format, if your input does not appear in the
drop down menu then check the format in the history panel.

**Counts Data**
      
A matrix of expression level with rows corresponding to particular genes
and columns corresponding to the feature count in particular samples.
Values must be tab separated and there must be a row for the sample/column
labels and a column for the row/gene labels.::

    "Smpl1"	"Smpl2"	"Smpl3"	"Smpl4"	"Smpl5"
  "27395"		1699	1528	1463	1441	1495
  "18777"		1905	1744	1345    1291    1346
  "150370"	6	8	4	5	5
  "21399"		2099	1974	1574	1519	1654    
  "58175"		356	312	347	361	346
  "108664"	2528	2438	1762	1942	2027    
  "12421"		2182	2005	1786	1799	1858    
  "240690"	3	4	2	3	3
  "319263"	1337	1380	1004	1102	1000
  "71096"		0	0	2	1	6	
  "59014"		1466	1426	1296	1097	1175
  ...


NOTE: The column labels look misaligned with the columns due to the
presence of row labels, this is read correctly into R which proccesses the
data.

**Factor Levels**

The levels of your samples seperated by comma, no spaces should
be present and the order of the levels must correspond to the column order
of the samples in the input matrix. This input determines the colour of
the plot where the samples of the same level are given the same colour.
      
**Sample Labels**
      
The labels to the samples provided seperated by comma, no spaces 
should be present and the order of the labels should reflect the column 
order of the samples in the input matrix. This input determines the label 
plotted on to the MDS plot and the point corresponding to each sample will
be that sample's label.
      
**Label Size**
      
Scale factor for the size of labels, if the labels are too long in the
standard plot then this value should be reduced, if more visibility is
desired then this value can be increased. The scaling value is bounded
between 0 and 2.

    </help>
</tool>
